<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on CyberBored Blog</title>
    <link>https://cyberbored.site/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on CyberBored Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 10:31:35 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cyberbored.site/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://cyberbored.site/posts/ad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 10:31:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyberbored.site/posts/ad/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: Today I will be starting my first ever Active Directory Home Lab.
Requirements: - Virtual machine from any vendor of your choice.- Windows Server 2019 ISO.- Window 10 ISO.Requirements Installation: -VMware: Installation Link, Either press the provided link or search for Vmware Player Workstation, then simply scroll down and you will see the following picture:
Choose which version you want depending on the OS you are using and press download and simply install the app.</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I will be starting my first ever Active Directory Home Lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;- Virtual machine from any vendor of your choice.
- Windows Server 2019 ISO.
- Window 10 ISO.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;requirements-installation&#34;&gt;Requirements Installation:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-vmware&#34;&gt;-VMware:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vmware.com/products/workstation-player/workstation-player-evaluation.html&#34;&gt;Installation Link&lt;/a&gt;, Either press the provided link or search for Vmware Player Workstation, then simply scroll down and you will see the following picture:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/vmware/0.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose which version you want depending on the OS you are using and press download and simply install the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/vmware/1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/vmware/2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can add Enhanced Keyboard driver depending on preference, but it isn&amp;rsquo;t necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/vmware/3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/vmware/4.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/vmware/5.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/vmware/6.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And VMware would be installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-windows-server-2019&#34;&gt;-Windows Server 2019:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/evalcenter/download-windows-server-2019&#34;&gt;Installation Link&lt;/a&gt;, Either press the provided link or search for Windows Server 2019 and choose ISO downloads:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/0.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the installation is finished, head on to Vmware and follow the following steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After pressing create link you will be presented with this windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose I will install the operating system later, because if you choose ISO installation immediately you might face some installation error later on after lunching the server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/9.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/4.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/5.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The storage can be changed depending on your Disk and PC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/6.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure to add two network adapters, one that is dedicated for the internet that is going to be running NAT, and one dedicated for the internal VMware network (Host-Only). After setting up everything, right click on the newly created virtual machine for windows server 2019 and press settings .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/10.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or you can left click on the windows machine and you can find setting also under play the virtual machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/11.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you lunch the settings window, go to the CD/DVD (SATA) and choose Use ISO image file, then browse to where you downloaded your windows server ISO image and choose it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/12.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/13.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then after setting everything up correctly, we lunch the virtual machine. Note that once you lunch the Windows Server press enter in the machine window, because otherwise it would show a timeout error. It should show you an installation window, and that&amp;rsquo;s how you would know that it was setup correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/14.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/7.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%2010/6.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%2010/7.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%2010/8.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally setup your admin account, and you will be done with the installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-windows-10&#34;&gt;-Windows 10:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/software-download/windows10&#34;&gt;Installation Link&lt;/a&gt; Either press the provided link or search for Windows 10, and download Create windows 10 installation media:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%2010/0.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the installation is complete, lunch the installation media and follow the steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%2010/1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%2010/2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%2010/3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the installation is completed for the ISO file, follow the same steps for the machine setup as Windows server, but make sure to choose ISO file during the initial setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%2010/9.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%2010/10.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system configurations can be changed depending on your PC. After the setup is complete, lunch the machine and proceed with the setup&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%2010/4.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can choose either Windows 10 Home or Windows 10 Pro. Then proceed with the installation normally and setup a random Microsoft account or proceed without one by choosing limited options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;windows-server-2019-setup&#34;&gt;Windows Server 2019 setup:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After installing the requirements, we should setup everything to be able to start. We will start first by setting up windows server 2019 by creating a new virtual machine on your Virtual Machine, I chose VMware since it get updated more often, which is more secure and less vulnerable. Next, we should configure the network adapter setting for the internal network. To configure the network, we open control panel &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Network and Internet &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Network and Sharing Center &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Change adapter settings and you should have the following page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/16.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I renamed the two network adapters to internal and internet so that I would be able to tell the difference between them. To know which I simply pressed right click &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%2010/11.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%2010/12.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%2010/13.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one that has IPv4 connectivity is the one that is running on NAT, while the one that isn&amp;rsquo;t connected to anything is the internal internet adapter. After configuring the name, right click again on the internal adapter and choose properties, then go to the IPv4 and choose properties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/17.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/18.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the following IP addresses is where we configure the IP for the network.
After setting up your IP address the subnet mask should be assigned automatically according to the IP you setup and we won&amp;rsquo;t assign a default gateway, because the domain controller will serve as a default gateway, it has two NICs one on the internet and one on the inside and that&amp;rsquo;s why the internal NIC won&amp;rsquo;t have a default gateway. For the DNS server, when we install the active directory, it automatically installs the DNS and that&amp;rsquo;s why it will use itself as the DNS server. To achieve that we can either put its own IP address or the loop address 127.0.0.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/19.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;setting-up-active-directory-on-windows-server-2019&#34;&gt;Setting Up Active Directory on Windows Server 2019:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After setting up the network setting and configuring all the basics, it is time now to setup the main even Mr. Active Directory. To setup the AD, we need Server manager which is installed by default on the windows Server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/20.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we press the second option, which is Add roles and features and you keep first two tabs on default by pressing next until you reach server selection tab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/21.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over here we want to choose the server we want to install the active directory on, in my case I only have one server, so I simply will select it and press next to install the AD on it. Then choose Active Directory Domain services, then continue with next until you reach the result tab and press install.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/22.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/23.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the installation is done, close the installation page and you will have a warning sign on the flag located on the navigation bar, which says that you installed the AD Domain Services, but you didn&amp;rsquo;t configure it yet. Press on the flag then promote this server to a domain controller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/24.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you open the new tab to configure the AD, we want to choose a Add a new forest and choose a domain name then press next and setup a password for your service restore mode, then leave everything else on other tabs on default until you reach the Prerequisites Check where it will check if you have everything setup correctly, if it is all setup correctly you will be able to start the installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/25.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/26.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the installation is done, it will ask you to restart your system to install and apply all changes and you simply press close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/27.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the setup is done you will have a new account depending on the domain name you chose, in my case it was MR\ADMINISTRATOR. Login into the account and lets setup a new user, so that we refrain from using the built in admin account. To create the new account, press windows logo &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Windows Administrative Tools &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Active Directory Users and Computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/28.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/29.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After lunching the Active Directory Users and Computers, we want to create a new unit, press right click on the domain you created &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; New &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Organizational Unit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/30.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then name your new unit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/32.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we create the new unit we want to create a new user inside of the unit, press right click on the unit you created &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; New &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; User. Choose a name and password for your user, best practice in organizations is to put the first initial of the role - and the first name of the person&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/31.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/33.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/34.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The options under the password are optional, I turned off user must change password because it is a lab, and password never expires because it is a lab and I don&amp;rsquo;t want to always change it in a lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/35.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we have created our user, we need to configure user permissions to admin level, press right click on the user &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Properties &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Member of &amp;ndash; &amp;gt; Add. And type into the object name domain admins then switch to the new created user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/36.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/37.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/38.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/39.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, we need to install RAS/NAT, which is Remote Access Server/Network Address Translation to allow our windows client to be on the network privately and still connect to the internet. Same as last time with setting up the AD Domain Service, we choose Add roles and features in the server manager then leave everything on default for the first two tabs, but this time we need to add Remote Access option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/20.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/40.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the role service we need to add the routing feature, then we install the new features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/41.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the installation is done, we close the installation window. This time instead of pressing the yellow warning we need to choose tool tab &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Routing and Remote Access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/43.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then to configure the network to be active and able to connect to the internet, right click on DC (local) &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Configure and Enable Routing and Remote Access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/44.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then press next, and choose Network address translation (NAT) to enable us to connect to the internet while staying private.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/45.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, choose use this public interface to connect to the internet and choose the one that we named &lt;em&gt;INTERNET&lt;/em&gt; and is connected to the internet through NAT, then press next and finish to setup everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/46.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should have a similar window if everything was setup correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/47.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/48.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the next step, we want to setup the DHCP on our Domain Controller to allow our Windows 10 client to get on the internet. To setup the DHCP, we have to go back to the Add roles and features and we keep everything for the first two tabs on default, choose our server and add DHCP Server on the Server Roles, then next and install. After installation is done close the installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/49.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is time now to configure the DHCP, press Tools tab &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; DHCP. And you should have the following window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/50.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose either IPv4 or IPv6 &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; right click &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; new scope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/51.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/52.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, setup the scope name, for me I just named it after the range of the IP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/53.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, we need to setup the range of the IP that we want to give to our clients, depending on the size of your organization you can give out more IPs, but for now we can just keep it between 100-200.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/54.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, we have this window, which is just asking what IPs you want to exclude or reserve, in my case I left it empty as I don&amp;rsquo;t need to exclude any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/55.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next window, we have the Lease Duration, which reserve an IP for a period of time for the user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/56.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next window, asks us if we want to configure the DHCP option, which tells the client which server to choose for DNS or Gateway, and since we want to allow the client to get on the internet, we should choose yes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/57.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over here we are choosing the default IP for the gateway to allow the client to connect to the internet, and I chose the Domain Controller&amp;rsquo;s IP, since I want to be the gateway, then press add. For the following windows keep everything on default and finish the setup. After the setup is complete, we want to authorize our server and refresh it so that it comes online. To do so, right click on the DC server and press authorize, then right click again and refresh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/58.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we should see something like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/59.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For testing purposes we will temporarily turn on the ability to browse the internet on the DC without interruptions by security popups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To allow access to the internet, navigate to server manager and press configure this local server &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; IE Enhanced Security Configuration and turn off both available options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/60.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/61.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/62.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, we need to download a PowerShell script which Josh Madakor provide us that will help us to create all users Link Reference. After the installation is finished, save the zip file somewhere easy to access and extract the files inside. Navigate to the name.txt and add a name of a user you want to create (Optional). After you setup the name of users you would like to add, navigate to the windows icon &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Windows PowerShell Folder &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; PowerShell ISE (Run as administrator).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/63.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you lunch the PowerShell, open 1_CREATE_USERS file that we downloaded by opening the folder button that has a red circle in the picture bellow and run the command in the picture bellow &amp;lsquo;Set-ExecutionPolicy Unrestricted&amp;rsquo; and press yes to all. Note: in a real environment don&amp;rsquo;t allow any unknown PowerShell file to run unrestricted, as this would cause security breach in case of a malware was present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/64.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple explanation for the command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/65.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, navigate to the folder we downloaded to be able to pull the names that are in the name.txt file and run the script. You can either let the script run or just stop it after certain amount of users are created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/66.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the script is done you can navigate back to Active Directory Active Users and Computers to check all the created users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/67.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the final step on DC we need to create a router on the DHCP server. To create it we just need to navigate back to the DHCP &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; DC server that we created &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; IPv4 &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Server Options &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; right click &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Configure Options &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; 003 Router &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; and add the default gateway IP address. Then restart the server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/68.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/69.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%20server/70.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows 10 Client:
Now all that&amp;rsquo;s left for us to do is just configure the windows 10 client by following the steps in the requirements to set the initial setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%2010/16.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we need to setup the users, navigate to settings &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; System &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; About &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Rename this PC (advanced) &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Change… &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; add the name of the computer and the domain &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; add user name and password of one of the users we added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%2010/17.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%2010/14.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%2010/15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%2010/20.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you setup the user the pc will restart and you have to enter the user name and password, then everything should be setup. You can check if the user is connected by using ipconfig and pinging mydomain.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/images/AD/windows%2010/21.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Networkservice 1</title>
      <link>https://cyberbored.site/posts/networkservice1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 16:30:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyberbored.site/posts/networkservice1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: Server Message Block(SMB) is a client-server communication protocol used for sharing access to files, printers, serial ports and other resources on a network.
Enum4linux is a tool used to enumerate SMB shares on both Windows and Linux systems. It is basically a wrapper around the tools in the Samba package and makes it easy to quickly extract information from the target pertaining to SMB. This tool is always used after conducting port scan and SMB port is open.</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Server Message Block(SMB) is a client-server communication protocol used for sharing access to files, printers, serial ports and other resources on a network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enum4linux is a tool used to enumerate SMB shares on both Windows and Linux systems. It is basically a wrapper around the tools in the Samba package and makes it easy to quickly extract information from the target pertaining to SMB. This tool is always used after conducting port scan and SMB port is open.
The syntax of Enum4linux: enum3linux [flag] ip.
Flags for Enum4linux:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;TAG&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;FUNCTION&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-U&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Get userlist.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-M&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Get machine list.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Get namelist dump (different from -U and -M).&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-S&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Get sharelist.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-P&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Get password policy information.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-G&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Get group and member list.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-a&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;All of the above (full basic enumeration).&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;practical&#34;&gt;Practical:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I started by scanning the open ports using nmap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/pic0.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I searched for the group name, OS version, and the machine name using the following command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/pic1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/pic2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/pic3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After finding the OS version and important sharenames:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/pic4.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which I used to connect to the target using the group name, share name, and anonymous username:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/pic5.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried all the available files in the directory by downloading them using get and printing the results inside the file using cat, and the only file I was able to get information from was the Working text file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/pic6.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/pic7.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which also allowed me to learn that the target was using SSH to connect to the company&amp;rsquo;s network from his home due to the pandemic. After gathering this information, I navigated to a directory called .ssh which contained few important files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/pic8.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After downloading the file id_rsa and moving it to the .ssh file and then using the more command to access the name of the target through the id_rsa.pub file, which is cactus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/pic9.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/pic10.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/pic11.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/pic12.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting the name and the private key, I accessed the target through ssh and immediately found the flag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/pic13.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;brief-summary-about-telnet&#34;&gt;Brief Summary about Telnet:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Telnet is a network protocol that allows users to establish a command-line connection to a remote device over a network. A key note to keep in mind about Telnet is that it runs its transmitted packets unencrypted, which makes it easy and simple to capture and read all the plain text packets. Best practice is to replace Telnet with the more secure option SSH. Telnet can be run using the following command: &amp;rsquo;telnet[ip][port]&#39;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;practical-1&#34;&gt;Practical:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started by scanning the target using nmap to check for open ports, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to find any of the 1000 well known ports opened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/pic14.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/pic15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I switched to a different flag, which is the all port scanning flag to get a wider range of ports to scan, which found 1 port opened that I have never seen before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/pic16.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/pic17.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried figuring out what this service was used for, but it was a little bit of a brain scratch so I searched up port 8012 to learn what is it used for and apparently it is used for a trojan or a backdoor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/pic18.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I scanned again the port using nmap, but only port 8012 to get detailed information about it and its version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/pic19.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/pic20.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned from the scan that it is called SKIDY&amp;rsquo;S BACKDOOR. After learning these information, I used the opened port 8012 to connect to the target machine using telnet, and it immediately I was in, but all commands I input doesn&amp;rsquo;t return any output. I ran tcpdump in the background to listen to any ICMP message and used ping to check if the target is active.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/pic21.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/pic22.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/pic23.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the machine is online and reachable, I am able to execute commands. Which why I used msfvenom to generate a reverse shell payload.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/pic24.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;• -p = payload.
• lhost = our local host IP address (this is your machine&#39;s IP address).
• lport = the port to listen on (this is the port on your machine).
• R = export the payload in raw format.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, using netcat to listen to port 4444, I connected again to the target using telnet and ran the command that msfvenom generated to gain access to the target and get the flag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/pic25.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/pic26.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/pic27.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;brief-summary-about-ftp&#34;&gt;Brief Summary about FTP:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;File Transfer Protocol is a standard network protocol used for transferring files between a client and a server on a computer network. FTP allows users to authenticate themselves using a username and password to access files stored on a remote server. While FTP is convenient for file sharing, it has security vulnerabilities, such as transmitting data, including login credentials, in plain text. To address these security concerns, Secure FTP (SFTP) and FTPS (FTP Secure) protocols have been developed, which provide encryption and enhanced security for file transfers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;practical-2&#34;&gt;Practical:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the FTP practical lab, as tradition I scanned the target ports using nmap to find open ports, and only 2 ports were available 21 and 80. We can see that there is a file called PUBLIC_NOTICE.txt on FTP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/pic28.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/29.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/30.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;
And using ftp, I connected to the target using anonymous username and downloaded the file that was available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/31.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it isn&amp;rsquo;t really useful, I needed to gain privilege escalation on the target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Hydra is a very fast online password cracking tool, which can perform rapid dictionary attacks against more than 50 Protocols, including Telnet, RDP, SSH, FTP, HTTP, HTTPS, SMB, several databases and much more. Hydra comes by default on both Parrot and Kali, however if you need it, you can find the GitHub here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some important flags that we will use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Section&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Function&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;hydra&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Runs the hydra tool.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-t 4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Number of parallel connections per target.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-l [user]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Points to the user who&amp;rsquo;s account you are trying to compromise.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-P[path to dictionary]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Points to the file containing the list of possible passwords.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-vV&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sets verbose mode to very verbose, shows the login+pass combination for each attempt.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;[machine IP]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ftp / protocol&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Set the protocol.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/32.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By simply setting up the username number of parallel connections, path of the password lists, verberose to be able to see the passwords used, IP address of the target and protocol we want to run it on, hydra tool started spraying passwords on FTP username mike and I just waited for the tool to find the correct password. Depending on your device it might take some time. Fortunately for me, mike had an easy and well-known password. For the next step, I used the new found credentials to login to the target and gain access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/33.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/networkservice/34.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I finally gained the final flag, which allowed me to complete the room.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devil Machine</title>
      <link>https://cyberbored.site/posts/htb/devil/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 22:33:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyberbored.site/posts/htb/devil/</guid>
      <description>My personal walk through: I started today with my first ever machine after the starting point training. I first connected to the htb openvpn service and started searching the ports and versions of the port using nmap:
After that, I accessed the ftp open port and tried downloading and uploading some files using get and put, which allowed me to learn that I am on root privilege. Then, I started searching and learning about BurpSuit Reference which I used to intercept the websites requests.</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-personal-walk-through&#34;&gt;My personal walk through:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started today with my first ever machine after the starting point training. I first connected to the htb openvpn service and started searching the ports and versions of the port using nmap:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../../images/htb/pic0.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, I accessed the ftp open port and tried downloading and uploading some files using get and put, which allowed me to learn that I am on root privilege. Then, I started searching and learning about BurpSuit Reference which I used to intercept the websites requests. I learned then that the website version is Microsoft IIS httpd 7.5, which after doing a little research I learned that it uses aspx file extension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, after gathering all that information I searched msfvenom for windows payloads to make a payload in the aspx extention and uploaded it to the server using ftp put command and used msfconsole to lesson for sessions using the multihandler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../../images/htb/pic1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../../images/htb/pic2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I faced an issue, where the msfconsole wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to connect and the two reasons why are 1- I was using windows/x64/meterpreter/reverse_tcp instead of windows/meterpreter/reverse_tcp and 2-I forgot to set the payload in msfconsole, but now it works fine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../../images/htb/pic3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting access, I typed the command sysinfo to check for the architecture of the machine and after that shell followed with systeminfo to check to learn about the hotfixes installed which
turned out to be never updated&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../../images/htb/pic4.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../../images/htb/pic5.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then using the command background, I set the session to keep running in the background and then searched for suggester, which is used to suggest exploits for a specific machine then set my session and run the suggester, which gave me multiple exploits to use, so
I picked the first option and setup all required options&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../../images/htb/pic6.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, I had privilege escalated to root user and navigated from windows file to users file and got the flags using type command to display the flag on the screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../../images/htb/pic7.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nmap</title>
      <link>https://cyberbored.site/posts/nmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 14:43:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyberbored.site/posts/nmap/</guid>
      <description>Embarking on a new Nmap project today, I&amp;rsquo;m diving into the realm of testing and exploring device scanning.
To kick things off, it&amp;rsquo;s fascinating to note that every network-enabled computer boasts a whopping 65535 open ports. Out of these, 1024 are well-known ports that add an intriguing layer to our journey.
Key flags to keep in mind:
Flags Description -sS Half-open or stealth scan, which has similar function to TCP scan.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Embarking on a new Nmap project today, I&amp;rsquo;m diving into the realm of testing and exploring device scanning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To kick things off, it&amp;rsquo;s fascinating to note that every network-enabled computer boasts a whopping 65535 open ports. Out of these, 1024 are well-known ports that add an intriguing layer to our journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key flags to keep in mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Flags&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-sS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Half-open or stealth scan, which has similar function to TCP scan. Key difference between the two scan is that TCP scan performs.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-sT&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TCP connect scans, which performs 3-way handshake.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-sU&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;UDP connect scans, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t rely on the handshake.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-sN&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NULL scans, TCP request is sent with no flag set at all, and receives RST if port is closed.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-sX&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Xmas scans, sends malformed TCP packet and expects RST response for closed ports. It is called Xmas, as it sends(PSH, URG and FIN) which give it the appearance of a blinking Christmas tree.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-sF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FIN scans, similar to the NULL scan, but sends with a FIN flag.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-O&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Detects which operating system the target is running.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-sV&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Detects the version of the services running on the target.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-v, vv, vvv&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Verbosity is used to scan with in depth details.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-oA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Outputs Nmap results in three major formats.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-oN&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Saves Nmap results in normal format.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-oG&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Saves Nmap results in gerpable format.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Aggressive mode, which activates service detection, operating system, traceroute, and script scanning.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-T1-5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Timer template from level 1-5.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-p&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Port scan, can be used to specify the ports to be scanned.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-p-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;All ports scan, as the name suggest it scans all open ports.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;ndash;script&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Activates Nmap scripts.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-sn&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ping sweep, depends on ICMP message, which is sent to all specified IP addresses.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-Pn&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tells Nmap to scan without pinging the target in other words Nmap assumes that the target is alive.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-f&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Used to fragment the packets.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;ndash;mtu &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Similar to the use of fragmented packet, but allows you to control the size of the packet.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;ndash;scan-delay &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;ms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Used to add a delay between packets sent.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;ndash;badsum&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Used to generate in invalid checksum for packets. However, firewalls might respond automatically, without bothering to check the checksum of the packet. Which allows this flag to check the presence of firewall/IDS.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Nmap Scripting Engine (NSE) serves as a potent augmentation to Nmap, significantly expanding its capabilities. Written in the Lua programming language, NSE Scripts empower a wide spectrum of functionalities, ranging from vulnerability scanning to automated exploit deployment. While its applications are diverse, NSE&amp;rsquo;s remarkable utility lies in reconnaissance, yet it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to acknowledge the extensive script library at play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NSE scripts can be classified into different categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;• safe: Won&#39;t affect the target
• intrusive: Not safe: likely to affect the target
• vuln: Scan for vulnerabilities
• exploit: Attempt to exploit a vulnerability
• auth: Attempt to bypass authentication for running services (e.g. Log into an FTP server anonymously)
• brute: Attempt to brute force credentials for running services
• discovery: Attempt to query running services for further information about the network (e.g. query an SNMP server).
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, to execute a script, use the command &amp;lsquo;&amp;ndash;script=&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;&amp;ndash;script=vuln&amp;rsquo;. Multiple scripts can run concurrently with a command like &amp;lsquo;&amp;ndash;script=smb-enum-users,smb-enum-shares&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certain scripts require arguments, such as credentials for authenticated vulnerabilities, which can be provided using the &amp;ndash;script-args Nmap switch. Example: &amp;rsquo;nmap -p 80 &amp;ndash;script http-put &amp;ndash;script-args http-put.url=&amp;rsquo;/dav/shell.php&amp;rsquo;,http-put.file=&amp;rsquo;./shell.php&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For further assistance with scripts, utilize &amp;rsquo;nmap &amp;ndash;script-help &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nmap offers a formatted text file detailing filenames and categories for available scripts, which can be located at &amp;lsquo;/usr/share/nmap/scripts/script.db&amp;rsquo;. To search for scripts, you can use commands like &amp;lsquo;grep &amp;ldquo;gtp&amp;rdquo; /usr/share/nmap/scripts/script.db&amp;rsquo; or &amp;rsquo;ls -l /usr/share/nmap/scripts/&lt;em&gt;ftp&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;. Comprehensive scripts and libraries can be explored via this reference: &lt;a href=&#34;https://nmap.org/nsedoc/&#34;&gt;https://nmap.org/nsedoc/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To install/update the script list, consider these approaches:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1-Run &amp;lsquo;sudo apt update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo apt install nmap&amp;rsquo;.
2-Use &amp;lsquo;sudo wget -O /usr/share/nmap/scripts/&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.nse &lt;a href=&#34;https://svb.nmap.org/nmap/scripts/&#34;&gt;https://svb.nmap.org/nmap/scripts/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.nse&amp;rsquo;, followed by &amp;rsquo;nmap &amp;ndash;script-updatedb&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;practical-lab&#34;&gt;Practical Lab:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To initiate, I commenced by sending a ping to the target using the command &amp;lsquo;ping -c 5 10.10.239.246&amp;rsquo;. The purpose was to discern if the target would reciprocate with an ICMP response—a standard practice in network diagnostics. Subsequently, I employed &amp;lsquo;ping -h&amp;rsquo; to explore the array of available flags. Notably, the -c flag came into play, dictating the halt of pinging after five responses were received from the target. This parameter was selected to govern the desired extent of the ping operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/nmap/pic0.png&#34; alt=&#34;Xmas scan&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the displayed outcomes, it was evident that the target did not acknowledge the receipt of packets. Moving forward, I conducted an assessment to determine the status of the first 999 ports through an Xmas scan. The endeavor involved specifying the range of ports to be examined using the &amp;lsquo;-p&amp;rsquo; flag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/nmap/pic1.png&#34; alt=&#34;TCP scan&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scan revealed the ports in an open but disregarded state. Subsequently, I identified an issue with my openvpn setup, which was rectified by generating a fresh openvpn configuration file via TryHackMe. With the hurdle overcome, I proceeded to re-execute the nmap scans for open ports, this time employing a TCP scan. The result brought to light the presence of 5 accessible ports:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/nmap/pic2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Script&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concluding the process, I harnessed &amp;rsquo;nmap &amp;ndash;script&amp;rsquo; to scrutinize port 21 FTP, assessing its potential for facilitating access to the target. As a culmination, I successfully employed the anonymous username to establish a login into the target&amp;rsquo;s FTP server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/nmap/pic3.png&#34; alt=&#34;result&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/nmap/pic4.png&#34; alt=&#34;login&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/nmap/pic5.png&#34; alt=&#34;login&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash Shell Scripting</title>
      <link>https://cyberbored.site/posts/bashscript/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 04:32:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyberbored.site/posts/bashscript/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: I started by checking out what shell is running in our terminal using echo $SHELL.
Then using the command ls I listed the available files and directories in our working directory, and after that I listed the long format of the directories and files including the hidden ones using -la. After checking the current data available using ls, I typed pwd to check my current working directory. Next using cd / I navigated to the root directory which is located at the top of all directories, which contains sensitive files.</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started by checking out what shell is running in our terminal using echo $SHELL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/bash/pic0.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then using the command &lt;strong&gt;ls&lt;/strong&gt; I listed the available files and directories in our working directory, and after that I listed the long format of the directories and files including the hidden ones using &lt;strong&gt;-la&lt;/strong&gt;.
After checking the current data available using ls, I typed &lt;strong&gt;pwd&lt;/strong&gt; to check my current working directory. Next using &lt;strong&gt;cd /&lt;/strong&gt; I navigated to the root directory which is located at the top of all directories, which contains sensitive files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;manipulating-files&#34;&gt;Manipulating files:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used &lt;strong&gt;touch&lt;/strong&gt; command to create a file name myBashScript then used &lt;strong&gt;ls -l myBashScript&lt;/strong&gt; to list my new file and check that it was created successfully, I decided next that I would like to change the name of the file using the command &lt;strong&gt;mv myBashScript muchBetterName&lt;/strong&gt;. Finally, I removed the file using rm muchBetterName.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/bash/pic1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Commands&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I tried cat command which stands for concatenate, to list the contents of a file and redirect the contents into another file. First, I made a file called myNewFile.txt and using the command &lt;strong&gt;echo &amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo; &amp;gt; myNewFile.txt&lt;/strong&gt; to output the phrase hello world into the file, then &lt;strong&gt;cat myNewFile.txt&lt;/strong&gt; to output the content on the screen. Next, I used the command &lt;strong&gt;cat myNewFile.txt &amp;gt; test.txt&lt;/strong&gt; and finally displayed it using cat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/bash/pic2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Commands1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using more and less you can view all the content of the file or portion of them. I used nano to edit the contents of the files I created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;finding-information&#34;&gt;Finding Information:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried creating a new directory using mkdir and moved it to a new directory called backups and created two new files into it, then we deleted the whole file using rm -r backups because rmdir only deletes empty directories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/bash/pic3.png&#34; alt=&#34;create&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to find a directory using find command, which displayed a bunch of errors then tried it again but I added 2&amp;gt;dev/null which outputs all the errors into the file called null. By using * to be able to get all files and directories that has backup in their names.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/bash/pic4.png&#34; alt=&#34;find&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next I tried the grep command to find specific files that contains regular expressions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/bash/pic5.png&#34; alt=&#34;grep&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned that using &lt;strong&gt;!ls&lt;/strong&gt; I can access the content since last time I used ls. Using &lt;strong&gt;history&lt;/strong&gt; I can check the history of all commands I used in my CLI and &lt;strong&gt;man&lt;/strong&gt; is used to check the manual of a specific command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;aliases&#34;&gt;Aliases:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alias is a shortcut we can use to access a command that is frequently used, for example, &lt;strong&gt;ll&lt;/strong&gt; which is an alias for the command ls &lt;strong&gt;-alF&lt;/strong&gt;, we can check what an alias is for by typing &lt;strong&gt;alias ll&lt;/strong&gt;. We can create aliases by going to the file called &lt;strong&gt;.bash_aliases&lt;/strong&gt; which is checked when the shell is first lunched and checks the &lt;strong&gt;.bashrc&lt;/strong&gt; file. To create the aliase, we should run the following into the &lt;strong&gt;.bash_aliases&lt;/strong&gt; file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/bash/pic6.png&#34; alt=&#34;alias&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And replace the command that is after fbackup with the command you want to create an aliase for, and replace fbackup with the name that you desire for the alias command.
Note: When you first create an alias the shell won&amp;rsquo;t recognize it, since it only looks into the file once when it is first lunched, to make it look into the file and recognize the new alias we can type &lt;strong&gt;source .bash_aliases&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;writing-a-shell-script&#34;&gt;Writing a Shell Script:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started writing my first bash script. First, I created a file using nano and then using #!/bin/bash also known as the Shebang which specifies that the shell type is bash. Next, I wrote a comment to specify what this script is for so that in the future I can understand what it is made for. Then I set up variables and stored directory path into them. After that, to make sure that the file names aren&amp;rsquo;t the same, I assigned a variable that stores the date and I used back tick to let the shell know that it should execute the command that is inside of the back ticks, file name, and the file extension type, then combined them into a variable called FILE_NAME. After the script was create, I changed the file user permission using chmod to be able to execute the script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/bash/pic7.png&#34; alt=&#34;bash script&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/bash/pic8.png&#34; alt=&#34;script output&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I added tar to my script, which stands for tape archive and is used to create Archive and extract the Archive files. Using the command bellow allowed me to create and extracted the archived file using the following flags:
&lt;strong&gt;-c&lt;/strong&gt; which creates an archive by bundling files and directories together.
&lt;strong&gt;-f&lt;/strong&gt; Specifies the filename of the archive to be created or extracted.
&lt;strong&gt;-z&lt;/strong&gt; Uses gzip compression when creating a tar file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/bash/pic9.png&#34; alt=&#34;zip file&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reference used: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.geeksforgeeks.org/tar-command-linux-examples/&#34;&gt;https://www.geeksforgeeks.org/tar-command-linux-examples/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;bash-scripting-and-creating-a-cron-job-with-crontab&#34;&gt;Bash Scripting and Creating a Cron Job With Crontab:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final step, I started by creating an if else statement to check if the script is working and sends it to the specified email using the mail command else it will output that at that date something went wrong into the error.log file. Then, I used &lt;strong&gt;crontab -e&lt;/strong&gt; to automate the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/bash/pic10.png&#34; alt=&#34;extra code&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/bash/pic11.png&#34; alt=&#34;crontab&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
